A Finding Aid to the Clay Spohn Papers, circa 1862-1985, bulk 1890-1985, in the Archives of American Art
Archives of American Art
Clay Spohn papers
circa 1862-1985
bulk 1890-1985
Archives of American Art
Spohn, Clay Edgar, 1898-1977
AAA.spohclay
Archival Resource Key
20.4 Linear feet
The Clay Spohn papers measure 20.4 linear feet and date from circa 1862 to 1985 with the bulk of the material dating from 1890 to 1985. The collection consists of biographical material, correspondence, business records, notes and writings, art work, printed material, and photographs which reflect the life and career of painter and educator Clay Spohn.
Biographical Note
Clay Edgar Spohn was born November 24, 1898, in San Francisco, to Lena (Schaefer) and John Henry Spohn. From 1919 to 1921, Spohn studied at the University of California at Berkeley, and from 1922 to 1924, he studied at the Art Students League in New York under Kenneth Hayes Miller, Boardman Robinson, George Luks and Guy Pene Du Bois. He also became acquainted with Alexander Calder at the Art Students League. In 1924, Spohn was employed as an assitant designer to muralist Ezra Winter. From 1926 to 1927 he studied in Paris at the Academie Modern, a school run by Fernand Leger and Orthon Fireze.
Returning to San Francisco in 1927, Spohn became an active member in the Bay Area art scene. The Treasury Department commissioned him, in 1938, to execute a mural for the Montebello, California post office, and in 1939, he completed another mural under the sponsorship of the WPA for Los Gatos Union High School in Los Gatos, California.
In 1942, the San Francisco Museum of Art mounted Spohn's solo exhibition "Fantastic War Machines and Guerragraphs", consisting of a series of drawings inspired by dreams of World War II. From 1945 until his resignation in 1950, Spohn was employed as instructor of drawing and painting at the California School of Fine Arts, where he befriended Clyfford Still and Mark Rothko. In 1949, at the California School, he organized a group exhibition entitled "The Museum of Unknown and Little Known Objects", in which Spohn's extraordinarily-constructed objects were a focal point.
Spohn moved to Taos, New Mexico in 1952, and participated in several national exhibitions. He was Visiting Lecturer at Mount Holyoke College, Massachusetts, in 1958, after which he moved to New York City where he executed a series of paintings under the sponsorship of the collector J. Patrick Lannan. From 1964 to 1969, he taught at the School of Visual Arts in New York.
After a two year move to Taos, Spohn returned to New York in 1971. In 1974, the Oakland Museum sponsored a retrospective of Spohn's work.
Clay Spohn died in New York City on December 19, 1977.
Scope and Content Note
The Clay Spohn papers measure 20.4 linear feet and date from circa 1862 to 1985 with the bulk of the material dating from 1890 to 1985. The collection consists of biographical material, correspondence, business records, notes and writings, artwork, printed material, and photographs reflecting the life and career of painter and educator Clay Spohn.
Part 1 includes sketchbooks with annotated drawings by Spohn, writings including reminiscensces by Spohn, letters, clippings, and photographs of Spohn's artwork.
Part 2 includes biographical material; correspondence between Spohn and his colleagues; business records such as Spohn's general accounting records; Spohn's notes and writings on a variety of subjects; drawings and sketchbooks; printed material such as exhibition announcements and catalogs; and photographs of subjects such as Spohn, his family and colleagues, his house, and his artwork.
Arrangement
The collection is arranged into three parts. Part 1 was lent to the Archives of American Art in 1964 by Clay Spohn, and was microfilmed and returned to Spohn. Part 2 was donated to the Archives of American Art by Urban Neininger in 1978 and was partially microfilmed. Because material from part 2 was not processed until over three decades after filming Part 1, the overall organization is inconsistent. In general, material within folders is arranged chronologically.
Missing Title
Part 1: Clay Spohn Papers, 1926-1963
Part 2: Clay Spohn Papers, circa 1862-1985 (boxes 1-22, OV 23, 19.9 linear ft.)
Part 3: Addition to the Clay Spohn Papers, 1958-1977 (box 24; 0.4 linear ft.)
Provenance
The material on reel D169 was lent for filming by Clay Spohn in 1964. The material on reel 5461-5474 was donated by Spohn's friend and the executor of his estate, Urban Neininger, in 1978. An additional 0.4 linear feet of papers were donated by Spohn's biographer, David Beasley, in 2008.
Restrictions on Access
The collection is open for research. Use of unfilmed material requires an appointment.
Alternative Forms Available
Portions of the collection and materials lent for microfilming are available on 35mm microfilm reels D169, and 5461-5474 at the Archives of American Art offices and through interlibrary loan. Researchers should note that the arrangement of the collection as described in this finding aid does not reflect the order of the collection on microfilm.
Separated Materials
The Archives of American Art also holds material lent for microfilming (D169) including sketchbooks, writings, correspondence, and related material. Lent materials were returned to the lender and are described in the first series of the finding aid.
Drawings; Sketchbooks; Painting, Modern -- 20th century -- New York (State) -- New York; Account books; Ambrotypes; Photographs; Painting, Abstract -- France -- Paris; Rothko, Mark, 1903-1970; Corbett, Rosamond Walling Tirana, 1910-1999; Fryworth, Teressa, 1906-1981; Corbett, Edward, 1919-; Calder, Alexander, 1898-1976; Sievan, Maurice; Sihvonen, Oli, 1921-; University of California, San Francisco. School of Fine Arts; School of Visual Arts (New York, N.Y.); Reynal, Jeanne, 1903-; Ribak, Louis, 1902-1979; McChesney, Mary Fuller; Neininger, Urban; Still, Clyfford, 1904-
- Clay Spohn Papers (Microfilm), 1926-1963, undated; Series 1; Archival Resource Key
  Arrangement note
  1.1: Sketchbooks, 1926-1927
  1.2: Writings, 1963
  1.3: Correspondence and Related Material, 1939-1954, undated
  - Sketchbooks, 1926-1927; 1.1; Archival Resource Key
    Scope and Contents note
    The three sketchbooks found here contain notes and annotated drawings made by Spohn during his stay in Paris. Sketchbook I contains a drawing of Hemingway's friend, Musgrave, at Le Dome, schematic drawings for a "portable studio," and notes about what to take to Giverny. Sketchbook II contains a self-portrait drawing and one drawing each of Musgrave and Duff Twisden, Hemingway's model for "Brett" in The Sun Also Rises, with whom Spohn became acquainted in the cafes of Paris. Sketchbook III contains designs for chairs and notes giving advice on art.
    - Sketchbook I, [1926]; Archival Resource Key (Reel D169)
    - Sketchbook II, 1926-1927; Archival Resource Key (Reel D169)
    - Sketchbook III, 1926-1927; Archival Resource Key (Reel D169)
  - Writings, 1963; 1.2; Archival Resource Key
    Writings consist of Spohn's reminiscences in the form of a 100-page letter to sculptor and art historian Mary Fuller McChesney. He answers questions about his career and describes, with words and drawings, his works for the exhibition The Museum of Unknown and Little Known Objects at the California School of Fine Arts in 1949.
    - Writings (entitled "Reminiscences" on microfilm), 1963; Archival Resource Key (Reel D169)
  - Correspondence and Related Material, 1939-1954, undated; 1.3; Archival Resource Key
    Found here is a letter from Reginald Vaughn discussing the acquisition of Spohn's Los Gatos mural for the Morrison Center for Rehabilitation, a letter from the W.P.A. office concerning exhibitions, and three clippings. Also found are twelve photographs of artwork (primarily Spohn's murals) including: the mural The Legend of New Almaden; mural for a post office in Montebello, California; a mural for Castro Valley community center; a mural Fireman Save My Child for Volunteer Fire Department in Carmel, California; scale drawings of Benimino Bufano's proposed statue for Twin Peaks, San Francisco; and the lithograph Greek Legend.
    - Letter from Reginald Vaughn, 1954; Archival Resource Key (Reel D169)
    - Photographs of Work Executed Between, 1936-1939, undated; Archival Resource Key (Reel D169)
    - Letter from W.P.A., 1939; Archival Resource Key (Reel D169)
    - Clippings, 1936-1941; Archival Resource Key (Reel D169)
- Clay Spohn Papers, circa 1862-1985, undated; Series 2; Archival Resource Key; (boxes 1-22, OV 23, 19.9 linear ft.)
  2.1: Biographical Material, 1892-circa 1978 (box 1, 0.3 linear feet)
  2.2: Correspondence, 1925-1981, undated (boxes 2-5, 4.7 linear feet)
  2.3: Business Records, 1890-1983 (boxes 6-7, 1.6 linear ft.)
  2.4: Notes and Writings, 1924-1985 (boxes 7-18, 10.8 linear ft.)
  2.5: Artwork, 1926-1968, undated (box 18, sol 22, OV 23, 0.6 linear ft.)
  2.6: Printed Material, 1894-1977, undated (boxes 18-19, 1.5 linear ft.)
  2.7: Photographs, circa 1862-1977, undated (boxes 20-21, 0.5 linear ft.)
  2.8: Artifacts, undated (box 21, 1 folder)
  - Biographical Material, 1892-circa 1978; 2.1; Archival Resource Key; (box 1, 0.3 linear feet)
    Biographical material includes a variety of official documentation for Spohn and his parents. Documents concerning Spohn's parents include their marriage license. Documents concerning Spohn include his baptismal certificate, passport, the contents of two wallets, membership and identity cards, biographical sketches, two wills, and Spohn's death certificate. There is also a typescript biography of Spohn, "Life of a Painter," by David R. Beasley.
    Existence and Location of Copies
    Biographical materials are on reel 5461.
    - Documents Concerning Spohn's parents, 1892-1916; Archival Resource Key (Box 1, Folder 1)
    - Documents Concerning Clay Spohn, Archival Resource Key (Box 1)
      - Baptismal Certificate, 1898; Archival Resource Key (Box 1, Folder 2)
      - Naval Discharge Papers, 1918; Archival Resource Key (Box 1, Folder 3)
      - Passport and Identity Card for Travel in France, 1925-1926; Archival Resource Key (Box 1, Folder 4)
      - Contents of Wallet 1, 1941-1953; Archival Resource Key (Box 1, Folder 5)
      - Contents of Wallet 2, 1966-1977; Archival Resource Key (Box 1, Folder 6)
      - Membership Cards, 1951-1966; Archival Resource Key (Box 1, Folder 7)
      - Miscellaneous Identity Cards, 1958-1965; Archival Resource Key (Box 1, Folder 8)
      - Biographical Sketches and Résumés, 1932-1971; Archival Resource Key (Box 1, Folder 9-11)
      - Spohn's Medical History, 1964; Archival Resource Key (Box 1, Folder 12)
      - Wills, 1950-1969; Archival Resource Key (Box 1, Folder 13)
      - Death Certificate, 1977; Archival Resource Key (Box 1, Folder 14)
    - Typescript biography "Life of a Painter" by David R. Beasley, circa 1978; Archival Resource Key (Box 1, Folder 15)
  - Correspondence, 1925-1981, undated; 2.2; Archival Resource Key; (boxes 2-5, 4.7 linear feet)
    Correspondence is between Spohn and his colleagues, including two letters from Alexander Calder, eight letters from Mark Rothko, and twenty-eight letters from Clyfford Still.
    See Appendix for an alphabetical list of correspondents from Series 2.2.
    Appendix: Alphabetical List of Correspondents in 2.2
    Abend, George and Kitty Parker Abend (artists): 1950-1960 (4 letters)
    Abingdon Square Painters: 1958 (1 letter)
    Addison Gallery of American Art: 1958 (2 letters)
    American Artists' Congress: 1938 (1 letter)
    American Library of Color Slides: 1941 (1 letter)
    Anderson, Claude J. K.: 1958 (1 letter)
    Anderson, Wendell (poet): 1955-1956 (2 letters)
    Archives of American Art: 1964 (4 letters)
    Art Academy of Cincinnati: 1958-1959 (3 letters)
    Art Association of Newport: 1958 (1 letter)
    Art Career School: 1958 (1 letter)
    Artists Equity Association: 1950 (1 letter)
    Arts and Architecture: 1963 (1 letter)
    Art Students League: 1958-1964 (2 letters)
    Art Times: 1959 (1 letter)
    Art Workshop of the Rivington Neighborhood Asociation, Inc.: 1958 (1 letter)
    Ashton, Dore: 1969 (1 letter)
    Ayer, Phyllis: 1956 (1 letter)
    Bachels, Andrew: 1969 (1 letter)
    Barnett, Rici: 1973 (1 letter)
    Barron, John N.: 1966 (1 letter)
    Beasley, David and Viola: 1963-1978 (11 letters)
    Bender: Albert M. Bender Memorial Trust: 1947-1951 (2 letters)
    Bethers, Peggy: 1940 (1 letter)
    Blesh, Rudi: 1960 (1 letter)
    Board of Education, City of New York: 1958-1965 (2 letters)
    Booth, James W. (family friend): 1943-1956 (7 letters)
    Borgenight: Grace Borgenight Gallery, Inc.: 1965 (1 letter)
    Boru, Sorcha: 1932-1933 (12 letters)
    Brandenburg, Helen: 1970 (1 letter)
    Braunstein/Quay Gallery: 1977 (1 letter)
    Briggs, Ernie: 1967-1977 (2 letters)
    Bright, Beatrice: 1971-1973 (2 letters)
    Brock, Midu: 1954 (1 letter)
    Brooklyn Society for Ethical Culture: 1966 (1 letter)
    Brown, Lesley: 1955 (1 letter)
    Burke, Bob: 1971 (1 letter)
    Burnham, Janet B.: 1950 (1 letter)
    Bute, Janey: 1971 (1 letter)
    Calcagno, Lawrence: 1969-1977 (5 letters)
    Calder, Alexander: 1970-1972 (2 letters)
    California Palace of the Legion of Honor: 1964 (1 letter)
    California School of Fine Arts: 1955-1964 (2 letters)
    California: University of California at Berkeley: 1940 (1 letter)
    California: University of California at Santa Clara: 1975-1976 (2 letters)
    Carewe, Sylvia: 1969 (1 letter)
    Carr, James F.: 1967 (1 letter)
    Chase Manhattan Bank: 1971 (2 letters)
    Chisholm, Stuart (landscape architect): 1925 (1 letter)
    Clayton, Janice: undated and 1965-1974 (6 letters)
    Clifton, Jim and Mary (owners of a Spohn painting): 1956 (1 letter)
    College Art Association: 1949 (1 letter)
    Colorado Springs Fine Arts Center: 1952-1970 (4 letters)
    Cooke, Regina: 1955 (1 letter)
    Cooley, Anne: 1941 (1 letter)
    Corbett, Ed and Steff, and Rosamond Tirana: undated and 1951-1977(47 letters, including a 1962 wedding announcement for Corbett and Tirana, and a letter dated Mar 21, 1963 enclosing a photograph of Ed with an amputated foot)
    Craig, Jeanne: 1963 (2 letters)
    Crawford, Jane and Ernie: 1958 (3 letters)
    Crehan, Hub and Anne: 1960 (1 letter)
    Crewe, Sylvia: 1969 (1 letter)
    Crews, Judson and Mildred (publishers of poetry magazine in Taos): 1952-1969 (4 letters)
    Cumming, Ann (and Jennifer Sutcliffe): 1956 (1 letter)
    Cunningham, Ben: 1950 (1 letter)
    D'Arcangelo, Allan and Sylvia: 1965 (1 letter)
    Dasburg, Andrew: 1961 (1 letter)
    DePuy, John: 1964 (1 letter)
    Diebenkorn, Richard: 1951 (1 letter)
    Dilexi Gallery (L. James Newman): 1965 (1 letter)
    Dixon, Budd (J.B.) and Peggy: 1954-1970 (5 letters)
    Dowell-Kahl Gallery (Leone Kahl, director): 1963 (1 letter)
    Drumm, Steve: 1953 (1 letter)
    Durham, Charlotte: 1968-1970 (3 letters)
    D'Vorzon, Berenice and Randal Goya: 1965 (1 letter)
    East Hampton Gallery: undated (1 letter)
    Edwards, Tom L.: 1945-1974 (2 letters)
    Egri, Ted and Kit: 1958-1971
    Elster, Grace-Marion: 1926 (1 letter)
    Ely, Georgette and Wolcott: 1958-1969 (38 letters)
    Finichel, Lilly: 1954 (1 letter)
    Forster, Bertrand Dixon: 1961 (1 letter)
    Forster, Paul and Else: undated and 1943-1974 (15 letters)
    Fort Worth Art Center Museum: 1971 (1 letter)
    Foss, Florence: 1958 (1 letter)
    Fran, Ford: 1971 (1 letter)
    Fryworth, Teressa (Terry) (Registrar at California School of Fine Arts): 1950-1978 (72 letters)
    Fuller, Mary: see McChesney, Mary
    Fuller, Patti (Ed Corbett's niece): 1955 (2 letters)
    Furse, Roger: 1928-1953 (4 letters)
    Gallery of Modern Art, Taos, N.M.: 1972 (1 letter)
    Garcia, Enos: 1954 (1 letter)
    Georgiadis, Alex: 1951 (1 letter)
    Gettell, Mrs. Richard Glenn: 1958 (an invitation to meet Col. George Lincoln)
    Gluck, Heidi: 1977 (1 letter)
    Gomez, Dorothy Massey (mother of anthropologist Bill Massey): 1950 (1 letter)
    Gomez, Joe: undated and 1971 (2 letters)
    Grant, Bob: 1953-1972 (2 letters)
    Grant, Carolyn: 1969 (1 letter)
    Great Neck Board of Education: 1960 (1 letter)
    Grimm, Marjorie: 1973 (1 letter)
    Grossmann, Nancy: 1966 (1 letter)
    Guggenheim: John Simon Guggenheim Memorial Foundation: 1953-1954 (2 letters)
    Harwood Foundation: 1953-1956 (2 letters)
    Harris, Roger: 1973 (1 letter)
    Hawley, W. R.: 1977 (1 letter enclosing an exhibition catalog "Unemployed Wizards")
    Heischman, R. L.: undated (1 letter)
    Hill, Dorothy: 1967 (2 letters)
    Hocks, Fred: 1952 (1 letter)
    Howard, Ellen and Galen: 1957 (1 letter)
    Howard, Robert Boardman and Adaline Kent (San Francisco sculptors): 1951-1955 (2 letters)
    Howard, Madge Knight and Charles H.: 1946-1954 (21 letters)
    Hultburg, John and Lynne: 1959-1974 (5 letters)
    Huntsville Museum of Art: see Braunstein/Quay Gallery
    Hurst, Tricia: 1977 (1 letter)
    Hutchinson, Mrs. D. H.: 1925 (1 letter)
    Illinois: University of Illinois at Urbana: 1952 (2 letters)
    Jackson: Martha Jackson Gallery: 1965 (1 letter)
    Jacobson, Art (artist) and Ursula: 1950-1960 (9 letters)
    Jonson Gallery: 1969-1970 (2 letters)
    Kadish, Reuben: 1958 (1 letter)
    Kahl: Leone Kahl Gallery: 1964 (1 letter)
    Karnes, Marion Watson: undated and 1947-1954 (80 letters from Spohn)
    Keeney, James: 1963 (1 letter)
    Kieve, Rudolph: 1971 (3 letters)
    King, Vivie and Rufus: 1977 (1 letter)
    Kingman, Dong: undated calling card
    Kuhlman, Walt: 1957 (2 letters)
    Kultberg, Lynne and John: 1965 (1 letter)
    Labaudt, Lucien: 1943 (1 letter)
    Labaudt, Marcelle: 1956 (1 letter)
    Landgren, Paula: undated (1 letter)
    Lannan, J. Patrick (The Susquehanna Corporation/ The Lannan Foundation): 1966-1971 (4 letters); see Personal Business Records for correspondence pertaining to the Foundation's support of Spohn, 1961-1962
    LaPlante, John (Stanford University): 1949 (1 letter)
    Lazarus, Rosalind: 1960 (1 letter)
    LeBow-Gould Associates: 1958 (3 letters)
    Lee, Martha: 1957 (1 letter)
    Lehman, Margarett: 1957 (1 letter)
    Letter Shop: 1956 (1 letter)
    Library of Congress Copyright Office: 1932 (1 letter concerning the trisection of an arbitrary angle)
    Lippincott, Janet (artist): 1955-1956 (5 letters)
    Lockwood, Ward: 1952 (1 letter)
    MacAgy, Douglas and Betty: undated and 1945-1973 (13 letters)
    MacAgy, Jermayne (Jerry): 1945-1948 (2 letters)
    Macdowell Colony: 1975 (1 letter)
    Machcinski, Barbara: 1971 (1 letter)
    MacIntyre, Carlyle F.: 1945 (1 letter)
    Maes, Virginia: 1941 (1 letter)
    Mare, Doris and Emil: 1969 (1 letter)
    Marse, John J.: 1962 (1 letter)
    Marter, Joan: 1977 (3 letters)
    Martin, Agnes: 1958-1975 (3 letters)
    Massey, Ellen DeSelms: 1940 (2 letters)
    McCarthy, Francis Joseph (AIA): 1950 (1 change of address card)
    McChesney, Mary (Fuller) and Mac: 1952-1977 (62 letters, including one dated May 21, 1968 decorated with a lizard skin, one dated Jun 08, 1973 enclosing a wooden Yalalag Indian good luck charm, and one dated May 26, 1976 enclosing a photograph of group and McChesney art work at Temko mansion in Berkeley)
    McCormick, Herbert: 1951 (1 letter)
    McDonald, Katharyn: 1963-1964 (2 letters)
    Merlin Development Company: 1962 (1 letter)
    Merrick, Barbara: 1975 (1 letter)
    Meyer, Fleur Cowler: 1968 (1 letter)
    Miller, Dorothy (Museum of Modern Art): 1952-1977 (8 letters)
    Moore Dry Dock Company: 1942 (2 letters)
    Murphy, Jack W. and Dori (owners of some of Spohn's work): 1951-1976 (7 letters)
    Mygatt, Tony: 1954 (1 letter)
    National Collection of Fine Arts: 1977 (1 letter)
    Neininger, Urban and Jeanne: 1950-1976 (48 letters)
    New Mexico Highlands University: 1958-1969 (3 letters)
    New Mexico: Museum of New Mexico Art Gallery: 1952-1957 (3 letters)
    New Mexico: University of New Mexico at Albuquerque: 1957-1970 (2 letters)
    New York City Transit Authority: 1962-1963 (2 letters)
    New York Saucer Information Bureau: 1962-1965 (2 letters)
    New York University: 1958-1960 (3 letters)
    Oakland Museum (Terry St. John): 1970-1977 (33 letters)
    O'Connor, Francis V.: 1979 (1 letter)
    Ohio State University: 1958 (1 letter)
    Oldfield, Otis: 1942 (1 letter of recommendation for Spohn for Albert M. Bender Grants-in-Aid)
    Olmsted, Frederick: 1943 (1 letter)
    Oregon: University of Oregon: 1974-1975 (2 letters)
    Ortman, George: 1964 (2 letters)
    Otto, Curtis, Roberta, and Adrienne: 1957 (1 letter)
    Oxford University Press: 1949 (1 letter)
    Parrett, Fred C.: undated and 1954 (2 letters)
    Peale, Norman Vincent (office of): 1975 (1 letter)
    Pepsi-Cola Annual Art Competition: 1947 (2 letters)
    Peterson, Arline? and Pete: 1955-1957 (2 letters)
    Petrovo, Miriam: 1961-1971 (11 letters)
    Pitney, Peggy and Ed: 1948 (1 letter)
    Queens College: 1958 (2 letters)
    Ramsay, Anna R.: 1954 (1 letter)
    Rankine, Vivie (Mrs. Paul Scott Rankine): 1964-1981 (5 letters)
    Remington, Deborah: 1963 (1 letter)
    Reminick, Harry: 1954 (1 letter)
    Reynal, Jeanne: 1941 (an invitation to a reception for Arshile Gorky) and 1952 (1 letter)
    Ribak, Louis and Bea: 1954-1976 (5 letters)
    Richards, Tally: 1971-1980 (5 letters)
    Ridiman, Bob: 1963-1970 (4 letters)
    Rogoway, Marjorie and Rog: undated and 1953-1968 (15 letters)
    Rosebury, Amy and Ted: 1954 (1 letter)
    Rosen, Michael: 1970-1974 (4 letters)
    Roswell Museum and Art Center: 1977-1978 (6 letters)
    Rothko Foundation: 1971-1975 (4 letters)
    Rothko, Mark and Mell: 1946-1958 (8 letters)
    Rusnell, Wesley: 1972-1979 (13 letters)
    Sachs Gallery: undated and 1968 (2 letters)
    St. John's College: 1969 (1 letter)
    Salzer, Oscar: 1955 (1 letter)
    Sanders, Una and John: 1975-1977 (6 letters)
    Sands, Louis: 1948 (1 letter)
    San Francisco Art Association: 1939-1955 (19 letters)
    San Francisco Museum of Art: 1949-1977 (18 letters)
    Saxe, Suzanne: 1972-1973 (2 letters)
    Scarpitta, Pat and Sal: 1968 (1 letter)
    Schneiderwirth, Joan (friend of Ed Corbett): 1955 (1 letter)
    School of Visual Arts: 1964-1970 (86 letters)
    Schubart, Pauline: 1950 (1 letter)
    Shoemaker, Peter (former student of Spohn): 1955-1958 (5 letters)
    Shiras, Mary: 1958-1965 (10 letters)
    Sihvonen, Oli: 1953-1977 (66 letters)
    Slivka, David: 1954 (1 letter)
    Smith, Hassel: 1948 (1 letter)
    Spoerri, John: 1965-1977 (10 letters)
    Stables Art Gallery (Leone Kahl, director): 1956-1965 (14 letters)
    Stanford University: 1946 (1 letter)
    Stephens, Dick and Carolyn: 1960-1965 (3 letters)
    Stevens: Arthur Stevens Book Club: 1968 (1 letter)
    Still, Clyfford: 1948-1968 (28 letters, including one dated Nov 1950 to Ed Corbett, and one dated Nov 29, 1963 enclosing a hand-drawn map to Still's home)
    Strehler, Allen (Sociologist): 1954 (1 letter)
    Summers, Al: 1952 (1 letter)
    Sutcliffe, Jennifer (beautiful English girl who passed through Taos with Ann Cumming): 1956 (2 letters)
    Sznajderman, Marius: 1967 (1 letter)
    Taggart, Bill, Sandy, and Sean: 1968 (1 letter)
    Taos Artist's Association (Taos Art Association): 1956-1964 (6 letters)
    Taos Realty: 1968-1969 (3 letters)
    Tatarsky, Hy and Muriel: 1952-1957 (2 letters)
    Tatarsky, Stephanie: 1963-1964 (7 letters)
    Taylor, Gene: 1925 (letter of introduction to Erskine Gwynne)
    Temianka, Henri: 1941 (1 letter)
    Tensan, Keith and Gene: 1957 (1 letter)
    Terrain Gallery: 1960 (1 letter)
    Terry Art Institute: 1951-1952 (7 letters)
    Third Street Gallery (Helen Kaye, Director): 1950 (1 letter)
    Thomas, Corine (owner of a Spohn painting): 1954-1957 (7 letters)